So many dogs. So little time.
101 Dalmatians is a family, comedy film directed by Stephen Herek.
An evil, high-fashion designer plots to steal Dalmatian puppies in order to make
an extravagant fur coat, but instead creates an extravagant mess.
Cruella de Vil, played by Glenn Close.
Roger, played by Jeff Daniels.
Anita, played by Joely Richardson.
Nanny, played by Joan Plowright.
Jasper, played by Hugh Laurie.
Horace, played by Mark Williams.
101 Dalmatians is a 1996 American adventure comedy film produced by Walt Disney Pictures and
Great Oaks Entertainment, and distributed by Buena Vista Pictures Distribution.
Directed by Stephen Herek from a screenplay by John Hughes (who co-produces the film), it is a live-action remake of  Walt Disney’s 1961
animated film One Hundred and One Dalmatians, which was based on the 1956 novel The Hundred and One Dalmatians by Dodie Smith.
The film stars Glenn Close, Jeff Daniels, Joely Richardson, Joan
Plowright, Hugh Laurie, Mark Williams, and John Shrapnel.
Unlike the 1961 original film, none of the animals speak.
101 Dalmatians was released on November 27, 1996, and grossed $320.7 million in theaters against a $67 million
budget, making it the sixth-highest-grossing film of 1996, despite receiving mixed reviews.
Close was nominated for the Golden Globe Award for Best Actress in Motion Picture Musical or
Comedy, while the film was nominated for a BAFTA Award for Best Makeup and Hair.
The film explores themes of london, england, fur,
fashion designer, puppy, fur coat.
The tone is lighthearted.